Alden Davidson

adavidson@pm.me 570-412-3528 adavidson.us

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software engineering professional with experience developing and designing applications using modern web technologies. Strong interest in continuous learning and using new tools to improve products and processes. Adept at developing and deploying full-stack solutions with a relentless and passionate focus on user outcomes.

SKILLS.

Languages & Tools: Azure Kubernetes Services, CSS, Docker, Git, GNU/Linux, Kotlin, LATEX, MySQL, React, Spring Framework, TypeScript Practices: Continuous Integration, Extreme Programming, Test-Driven Development, User-Centered Design

WORK HISTORY

02/2024 – Current

SkillBridge Internship: Software Engineer

Sagely | Remote

- Built a social learning platform to guide users' professional learning journeys using AI to curate, organize, and contextualize online content.
- Worked on the three-developer team in a fast-paced start-up environment
- Gained valuable, personally novel experience with OpenAI's GPT, React Native, NativeWind, and Expo Application Services

01/2022 - 02/2024

Full-stack Software Engineer

United States Space Force | Los Angeles, CA

- Developed and sustained two full-stack applications for 1200+ space command & control users requiring worldwide availability
- Transitioned two applications from Cloud Foundry to Azure Kubernetes Services as tracers for new pipeline and deployment environment
- Practiced test-driven development at unit, integration, and end-to-end levels to ensure high code quality in continuous integration environment
- Participated in requirements gathering for high-visibility action to solidify prerequisites and determine best technical solution to meet user needs

11/2019 - 12/2021

Project Manager

United States Space Force | Los Angeles, CA

- Planned, scheduled, and negotiated \$28M follow-on for \$34M project
- Monitored project performance to identify and implement improvements
- Led cross-functional team of 8 to resolve project issues and mitigate risks
- Provided detailed project status updates to users, executive management, and other stakeholders

EDUCATION.

05/2019

Bachelor of Science: Computer Engineering

Rochester Institute of Technology | Rochester, NY